Last updated: October 2020

# Chiho Choi, Ph.D.

Computer Vision | Machine Learning

#### CONTACT INFROMATION

Honda Research Institute USA Inc. Website 70 Rio Robles, San Jose, CA 95134 LinkedIn chihochoi@outlook.com Google Scholar

## RESEARCH INTEREST

My research interest lies at the intersection of machine learning and computer vision, focusing on understanding and prediction of human behavior in a highly interactive environment. In this area, I build a new perspective for the safe operation of vehicles and robots designed to cooperate with humans.

Trajectory Forecast

Behavior Prediction

• Intention Prediction

• Uncertainty Modeling

Action Recognition

Pose Estimation

#### **EDUCATION**

Purdue University

West Lafayette, IN, USA

January 2018

Ph.D., Electrical and Computer Engineering

• Specialization: deep learning, 3D vision, recognition, tracking • Committee members: Karthik Ramani, Stanley H. Chan, Mireille Boutin, Jeffrey M. Siskind

University of Southern California

Los Angeles, CA, USA

M.S., Electrical Engineering

May 2013

• Specialization: 3D shape matching, registration

• Advisor: Prof. Suya You, Department of Computer Science

Hanyang University **B.S.**, Electronics and Computer Engineering Seoul, Korea

February 2011

Minor: Mechanical Engineering

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

Honda Research Institute USA

San Jose, CA, USA

Scientist

February 2018 – Present

- Leading multiple projects on recognition and prediction of human action, intention, and future behavior.
- Publications in CVPR (oral), ICCV, ACC, ICRA, IROS, CoRL, and NeurIPS.

**HERE Technologies** 

Chicago, IL, USA

Intern

May 2017 - August 2017

- Worked on traffic scene understanding for highly automated driving.
- Supervisor: Xiang Ma

## **PUBLICATIONS**

# **Refereed Papers**

[C13] J. Li\*, F. Yang\*, M. Tomizuka, and C. Choi. "EvolveGraph: Multi-Agent Trajectory Prediction with Dynamic Relational Reasoning". Proceedings of the Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS) 2020. arXiv: 2003.13924

[C12] C. Choi, S. Malla, A. Patil, and J. H. Choi. "DROGON: A Trajectory Prediction Model based on

- Intention-Conditioned Behavior Reasoning". Proceedings of the Conference on Robot Learning (CoRL) 2020. arXiv:1908.00024
- [C11] I. Dwivedi, S. Malla, B. Dariush, and C. Choi. "SSP: Single Shot Future Trajectory Prediction". Proceedings of the IEEE International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS) 2020. arXiv: 2004.05846
- [C10] S. Malla, B. Dariush, and C. Choi. "TITAN: Future Forecast using Action Priors". *Proceedings of the IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR)* 2020, oral. arXiv:2003.13886
- [C9] S. Bae, D. Saxena, A. Nakhaei, C. Choi, K. Fujimura, and S. Moura. "Cooperation-Aware Lane Change Maneuver in Dense Traffic based on Model Predictive Control with Recurrent Neural Network". *Proceedings of the American Control Conference (ACC)* 2020, to appear. arXiv:1909.05665.
- [C8] C. Choi and B. Dariush. "Looking to Relations for Future Trajectory Forecast". *Proceedings of the IEEE International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV)* 2019.
- [C7] C. Choi and B. Dariush. "Learning to Infer Relations for Future Trajectory Forecast". *In the IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR) Workshops 2019.*
- [C6] Y. Yao, M. Xu, C. Choi, D. Crandall, E. Atkins, and B. Dariush. "Egocentric Vision-based Future Vehicle Localization for Intelligent Driving Assistance Systems". *Proceedings of the IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA)* 2019.
- [C5] M. Liu, F. Yao, C. Choi, A. Sinha, and K. Ramani. "Deep Learning 3D Shapes Using Alt-az Anisotropic 2-Sphere Convolution". *Proceedings of the International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR)* 2019.
- [C4] C. Choi, S. Kim, and K. Ramani. "Learning Hand Articulations by Hallucinating Heat Distribution". *Proceedings of the IEEE International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV)* 2017.
- [C3] C. Choi, S. H. Yoon, C. N. Chen, and K. Ramani. "Robust Hand Pose Estimation during the Interaction with an Unknown Object". *Proceedings of the IEEE International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV)* 2017.
- [C2] **C. Choi**\*, A. Sinha\*, and K. Ramani (\* Co-first Author, order changed for emphasis). "DeepHand: Robust Hand Pose Estimation by Completing a Matrix Imputed with Deep Features". *Proceedings of the IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR)* 2016.
- [C1] C. Choi, A. Sinha, J. H. Choi, S. Jang, and K. Ramani. "A Collaborative Filtering Approach to Real-Time Hand Pose Estimation". *Proceedings of the IEEE International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV)* 2015.

#### **Non-Refereed Papers**

- [T5] C. Choi. "Shared Cross-Modal Trajectory Prediction for Autonomous Driving". arXiv preprint arXiv: 2004.00202, 2020.
- [T4] S. Su, C. Peng, J. Shi, and **C. Choi**. "Potential Field: Interpretable and Unified Representation for Trajectory Prediction". *arXiv preprint arXiv:1911.07414*, 2019.
- [T3] S. Malla, I. Dwivedi, B. Dariush, and **C. Choi**. "NEMO: Future Object Localization Using Noisy Ego Priors". *arXiv preprint arXiv:1909.08150*, 2019.
- [T2] **C. Choi**, S. Kim, J. H. Choi, and K. Ramani. "Embedding Compressive Layers in Deep Neural Networks". http://www.chihochoi.me/embedding.pdf, May 2017.
- [T1] **C. Choi** and S. You. "Dense and Reliable Shape Matching using 3D Particle Filtering". *CGIT Lab Technical Report, University of Southern California, May 2013.*

#### **Thesis**

[D1] C. Choi. "Computational Learning for Hand Pose Estimation". Ph.D. Dissertation, Purdue University, Jan 2018.

Last updated: October 2020

# PATENT APPLICATIONS

- [P16] S. Malla and C. Choi. "System and Method for Spatio-Temporal Multi-Modal Future Trajectory Forecast". Application pending.
- [P15] C. Choi. "System and Method for Shared Cross-Modal Trajectory Prediction". Application pending.
- [P14] J. Li and C. Choi. "System and Method for Trajectory Prediction with Evolving Interaction Graphs". Application pending.
- [P13] I. Dwivedi, S. Malla, C. Choi, and Behzad Dariush. "System for Single Shot Prediction using Composite Fields and Method Thereof". Application pending.
- [P12] S. Malla, C. Choi, and Behzad Dariush. "System and Method for Future Forecasting using Action Priors". Application pending.
- [P11] S. Su and C. Choi. "System and Method For Providing an Interpretable and Unified Representation for Trajectory Prediction". Application pending.
- [P10] S. Malla and C. Choi. "System and Method For Providing Future Object Localization Using Noisy Ego Priors". Application pending.
- [P9] A. Nakhaei, C. Choi, K. Fujimura, S. Bae, D. Saxena. "System and Method For Providing Cooperation-Aware Lane Change Control in Dense Traffic". Application pending.
- [P8] C. Choi. "Trajectory Prediction". Application pending.
- [P7] C. Choi. "Methods and Apparatuses for Future Trajectory Forecast". No. 16372058
- [P6] Y. Yao, M. Xu, C. Choi, and B. Dariush. "System and Method for Egocentric-vision based Future Vehicle Localization". Publication No. 20200086858
- [P5] X. Chen, X. Ma, S. Sood, and C. Choi. "Semi-automatic Training Data Selection based on High-dimensional Data Projection to Subspaces". Application pending.
- [P4] X. Chen, X. Ma, S. Sood, and C. Choi. "Deep Neural Machine for Lane Marking Style Classification based on Unwrapped Perspective Images". Application pending.
- [P3] X. Chen, X. Ma, S. Sood, and **C. Choi**. "Deep Neural Machine for Lane Marking Color and Material Classification based on Image Patches". Application pending.
- [P2] A. Sinha, C. Choi, J. H. Choi, and K. Ramani. "Method of training neural networks for hand pose detection". Patent No. US10503270
- [P1] A. Sinha, C. Choi, J. H. Choi, and K. Ramani. "Method and System for Hand Pose Estimation". Patent No. US10318008

# **TEACHING EXPERIENCE**

## **PhD Students Supervised / Mentored**

• Jiachen Li, from University of California Berkeley	September 2019 – Present
• Shan Su, from University of Pennsylvania	July 2019 – Present
• Sangjae Bae, from University of California Berkeley	June 2019 – September 2019
• Yu Yao, from University of Michigan	May 2018 – August 2018

#### **Teaching Assistant**

• Purdue University January 2015 – May 2015

ME 444: Computer-aided Design and Rapid Prototyping

Introduction to advanced computer-aided design (CAD) for product design, modeling, and prototyping.

• University of Southern California August 2012 – December 2012 CSCI-588 Specification and Design of User Interface Software (graduate-level course)

A design and implementation of user interface software relating to human/computer interaction.

Last updated: October 2020

## INVITED TALKS

Guest Lecturer, Purdue University

December 2017

• Introduction to Pose Estimation – Probabilistic models in computer vision

## **ACADEMIC SERVICES**

#### **Publication Committee**

Honda Research Institute USA

February 2020 – Present

## **Program Committee / Reviewer**

- IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR) 2018, 2019, 2020, 2021
- Association for Advancement of Artificial Intelligence (AAAI) 2020, 2021
- International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR) 2021
- IEEE Winter Conference on Applications of Computer Vision (WACV) 2021
- Asian Conference on Computer Vision (ACCV) 2018, 2020
- Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS) 2020
- European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV) 2020
- IEEE Intelligent Vehicles Symposium 2020
- IEEE Transactions on Intelligent Vehicles 2020
- IEEE International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV) 2019
- ACM CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems 2019
- IEEE Transactions on Image Processing 2018
- IEEE Transactions on Multimedia 2017

## **HORNORS**

National Science and Technology Scholarship

2003 - 2010

from Ministry of Education, Science and Technology, Korea

## **SKILLS**

Programming Languages Python, C/C++

Deep Learning Frameworks TensorFlow, PyTorch, Caffe, MatConvNet

Graphic Tools Unity, Blender

MCU Tools Code Vision, Code Composer Studio
CAD Tools PTC Creo Parametric, CATIA

## MEDIA COVERAGE

- Looking to Relations for Future Trajectory Forecast, ICCV Daily Magazine, October 30 2019.
- AI Can Predict the Future Location of Vehicles, NVIDIA NEWS Center, September 27 2018.
- Freeing Our Fingers: Handing Over VR's Toughest Challenge to GPUs, NVIDIA Blog, August 24 2016.
- AI and VR: New Experiments at Purdue University, ENGINEERING.com, June 30 2016
- DeepHand motion tracking enters the VR arms race, New Atlas, June 23 2016
- New tool for virtual and augmented reality uses 'deep learning', Purdue News, June 22 2016. https://youtu.be/RhIjq-MxcW0

# REFERENCES

Available Upon Request